OP
ED
今すぐとは言わないが
I won't ask for an answer right away, but
would you consider writing the story for this?
こっちの原作をやる事も考えてくれないか
えっ で でも
B-But... I can't do that unless Mashiro agrees to it.
それは真城の同意がなければできません
あっ すまん そうだな
Oh, sorry. That's right.
P 「PCP」に影響さえ出なければ 僕は…
A-As long as it doesn't interfere with PCP, I'm...
白鳥君にも 連載取ってほしいし
I do want Shiratori to get serialized.
高木にも原作者として もっと上に いってほしいので
And I want Takagi to progress as an author.
本当にいいのか
Are you sure it's okay?
Y-Yeah! Just don't make it better than PCP!
でも 「PCP」より面白くするなよ
とりあえず この読切は 高木君原作で出すのは決まりだな
Anyway, we'll submit this one-shot with Takagi as the author.
ネームを少し手直しして このまま原稿にしてもらう
Polish up your storyboard a bit, and make a manuscript from it.
は はい
Right.
そうだな  10月期の月例賞に出せるのが理想だが
Let's see... I would like to be able to submit this for October's Treasure,
応募締め切りまであと20日しかない
but there's only 20 days until the application deadline.
やはり 11月期か
Maybe we should shoot for November?
できます
I can do it! I can make a manuscript in 20 days!
20日で原稿にしてみせます
じゃあ このネームを すぐに原稿にできるようにしましょう
Then let's get this storyboard ready to make into a manuscript right away!
そうだな
Right.
はい
Okay!
まず 入りだが 人の会話を…
First off, here at the beginning...
He's standing still, watching people talk...
今のシュージンなら もう1本原作も不可能じゃない
Shuujin can handle two stories now.
でも もし連載まで いったら
But if this makes it to serialization...
ano ne moshimo ima sugu ni kimi no moto he to
Hey, if I could go to where you are right now
ikeru naraba kono koe ga nakunattemo ii ya
then I could accept losing my voice
mezasu basho ga amari ni mo tooku
The goals I've set myself seem impossible to reach,
boku wa mou michi ni mayoisou da
and I feel lost on my path
kowareta jishaku wo ate ni shiteru n da
I'm relying on a broken compass and hiding in another's shadow
dareka no kage ni kakurete sa
nanika wo te ni ireru tame nanika wo tebanasu nante koto wo
If we keep letting go of some things in order to find something else,
tsuzukete mo kitto bokura wa otona ni wa narenai
then I'm convinced we can never grow up
narenai
Never
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神字幕组---
台本:共由先生         翻译:   poopy    虫    繁化:烨语
校对：Astro      后期：福尔摩斯的手杖
阶段与手表
Step and Watch
さすがに 打ち合わせの連チャンは疲れた
Those two back-to-back meetings really took their toll.
「恋太＆ピース」いけるかな
I wonder if Rabuta & Peace will make it?
シュージンが原作なんだから いってもらわないと困る
You're the story author, so it had better!
だよな
You said it. We'd be in trouble if a
story by Ashirogi Mutou didn't make it.
原作 亜城木夢叶で選外とか やばいよな
原作 高木秋人だろ
You mean a story by Takagi Akito, right?
ああ そうか
Oh, right.
でも 本名は出したくないし 別のペンネームで
But I don't want to use my real
name. I'll have to use an alias...
ペンネームは変えるけど あくまでも 亜城木夢叶の次のための挑戦な
I'll change my alias.
But all this is just to prepare us
for the future of Ashirogi Mutou.
Yeah.
「PCP」を頑張って 次の作品で 必ずアニメ化しようぜ
Let's work hard on PCP and make sure our next work becomes an anime!
次の作品か
Our next work, huh.
そんなに この絵が好き
Do you love this painting that much?
うん
Yeah.
シュン よちよち歩きの時から よくここに来てじっと眺めていたものね
Ever since you could walk, you'd come in here and stare at that painting for hours.
ママ シュンのパリ留学を準備してくれてる
Mom is arranging your study-abroad in Paris.
よかったわね
Aren't you glad about that?
マンガ家って そんなに駄目かな
Is being a manga artist really that awful?
世間体もあるし シュンだって画家になりたいんでしょ
We have our appearances to keep up... and you wanted to be an artist, right?
この絵をこうして僕は見られるけど
I can come look at this painting,
おじいちゃんが 高いお金を出して独り占めしたんだよね
but Grandpa paid a lot of money to have it all to himself.
マンガは 少しのお金で たくさんの人が見る事ができる
Many people can read manga with just a little money.
たくさんの人に楽しんでもらえる
Many people can enjoy it.
マンガ家だって 立派な仕事だよ
Being a manga artist is a wonderful job.
よし よく描けてる
Good, it's well drawn.
20日で 45ページ よく描けたな
45 pages in 20 days!
You've done well!
正直 ここまでやれるとは 思わなかったよ
I'm honestly surprised you've gotten it this far.
これならいける
This will definitely pass!
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
アシスタントに入って ペン入れに慣れたのがよかったんだろうと思います
I'm glad I became an assistant and got experience in inking.
じゃ これは 月例賞に出すよ
I'll go ahead and submit this to Treasure, then.
お願いします
Thank you.
When you became an assistant, you had no intention of becoming a manga artist.
アシスタントに入る時
「マンガ家になる気はない 絵が描ければいい」って言っていたが
You were satisfied with just being able to draw.
今は マンガ家を目指す で いいんだよね
But I take it that you've changed your mind now, right?
はい
Right.
Editorial Department
Shounen
Jack
Jack SQ
バカ言うなよ
Don't be ridiculous!
いくら名前を変えたからって 連載作家の高木君が原作で月例賞に出せるか
Even if you change his name,
you can't submit a manuscript to Treasure when a serialized author like Takagi is doing the story!
Bleep bloop, Hitotsubashi, Chiyoda, Tokyo
Yuueisha Weekly Shounen Jack Editorial Department
Jack's February Treasure Amateur Manga Prize Coordinator
前に もめたの 忘れたのかよ
Bleep bloop, Hitotsubashi, Chiyoda, Tokyo
Yuueisha Weekly Shounen Jack Editorial Department
Jack's February Treasure Amateur Manga Prize Coordinator
Don't you remember what happened last time?!
あっ すっかり忘れてました
I... completely forgot.
今回は原作だけなので そんな事 考えもしませんでした
He's only doing the story this time, so I didn't think about it.
高木君原作ならネームの段階で見せろよ
If Takagi's the author, you should have shown it to me as soon as you had a storyboard.
どれ ちょっと見せてみろ
Well, hand it over.
はい
Right.
おっ 面白いな
This is great!
絵もいい こりゃ 「NEXT」か 本誌での掲載を狙うしかないぞ
The art's good, too!
With this, we could aim for NEXT, or even Jack!
いいんですか
Is that all right?
じゃなきゃ駄目だと言ってるんだ
I'm telling you, we have to!
なら 本誌を第一志望で お願いします
Then let's aim for Jack itself!
はい
Okay.... okay.... okay!
ありがとうございました
Thank you!
Takagi, he said that Rabuta & Peace will be
published in the November 24th issue of Jack!
高木さん
「恋太＆ピース」本誌11月24日号に 掲載が決まりました
えっ 本誌
What? It will?!
でも 月例賞に出したんじゃ
But I thought he submitted it to Treasure...
高木先生が原作だと 月例賞は 駄目らしくて
With Takagi as the author, apparently Treasure was off limits...
あ そうか
Oh, I see.
とにかく おめでとう
Anyways, congrats! It was a good idea to make Takagi your author!
やっぱり高木さん原作ってのがよかったんだよ
僕も そう思います
I think so too!
これでいい結果が出たら 服部さんはきっと連載の方向に
If it does well, Hattori will definitely push it towards serialization...
The timing was perfect. They just happened to have an opening for a one-shot...
いいタイミングで 読切枠が空いていたみたいで
シュージンが原作者として成長するのは いい事
It's good that Shuujin is growing as an author.
それは 間違いないんだ
I know that's true.
ただいま
I'm home.
Cut it out, Peace.
ピース やめろ
すごいんだぞ ピース
Peace, listen to this!
僕とピースをモデルに描いた僕のマンガが「ジャック」に載るんだ
The manga I drew based on you and me is gonna be in Jack!
母さん ただいま
Mom, I'm home.
シュン 「ジャック」って何なの
Shun, what is "Jack"?
「ジャック」は マンガ雑誌で
It's a manga magazine...
もう マンガの手伝いなんてやめなさい
Stop working as a manga assistant.
でも
But...
もう好き勝手は させませんから
I won't let you do as you please anymore.
マンガなんて くだらない
Manga is ridiculous.
Niizuma
Eiji  Ltd.
今週も2位
You're in 2nd this week, too.
亜城木君の頑張りがいい方向に出てるな
It looks like Ashirogi's tenacity is pushing you in a good direction.
はい 負けられません
Yes! I can't afford to lose!
「PCP」は まだ アニメになってないですし
PCP hasn't become an anime yet, after all.
いや 「PCP」のアニメ化は まず ないだろうん
Well, PCP probably won't ever become an anime.
何でですか 面白いのに
Why not?!
It's good!
ひと言で言えば完全犯罪マンガだからな
In short, because it's a perfect crime manga.
邪道の限界とでも言うかは
There's a limit to what you can do with "unorthodox"...
テレビ 根性ないですね がっかりです
TV stations have no backbone.
I'm disappointed.
順位的にも これ以上は 望めないだろうし
In terms of rankings, they can't
hope to get much better than this.
普通に やっていれば「CROW」が抜かれる事はない
If things go on like this, they won't surpass CROW.
Huh? This is weird.
おかしいですね
Hm? What is?
何が
Rabuta
& Peace
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
来週号 この「恋太＆ピース」
Rabuta
& Peace
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
Rabuta
& Peace
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
This "Rabuta & Peace" in next week's issue.
原作は 高木先生ですよね
Takagi's writing the story?
Yeah. He tried to rearrange his name, but you figured it out anyways?
おう 本名を もじっただけだから やっぱり分かったか
内容で分かりました
I figured it out from the story.
人間の本音の部分 高木先生の真骨頂 クセが出てます
This part about people's real feelings—
Takagi has a habit of writing about "people's true worth".
なるほど
I see.
「PCP」は アニメにならない「CROW」も抜けないって言いましたよね
You said that PCP won't get an anime and won't surpass CROW, right?
Y-Yeah.
じゃあ 何で高木先生はこんなの書いてるんですか
Then why is Takagi writing something like this?!
Original work:
Kido Takaaki
Manga:
Shiratori Shun
「何で」って言われても
Well, I don't really...
っていうか駄目か
Actually, why is that a bad thing?
駄目に決まってます
It's obviously wrong!
こんなの書いてちゃ駄目です 駄目駄目
He can't write this! It's wrong! Wrong!
Hattori Akira
Refuse
Accept
はい 高木です
Takagi speaking.
「PCP」4位
PCP is in 4th place?
「恋太」5位
Rabuta's in 5th?!
十分 連載を狙える順位
That's good enough to aim for a serialization.
Must-Have Photo Collection of Manga artists and Animators
よし 原稿はOKと
All right, the manuscript is good.
それで「恋太＆ピース」の方だが
So, about Rabuta & Peace...
I'm already writing PCP.
僕としては「PCP」もあるので まず連載用の原作を書くか書かないか
So whether or not I'm going to write the story for another serialization
そこから じっくり考えさせてほしいんですが
is something I'd like take some time to think about.
そうだな
You're right.
「PCP」が優先なのは分かってる
I know you want to prioritize PCP.
シュージン もし俺に気を遣ってるなら そんな事 考えなくていい
Shuujin, if you're worried about me, don't be. I'm fine.
サイコー
Saikou...
シュージンが レベルアップするのは俺だって素直にうれしいし
I'm honestly happy that you're improving yourself.
白鳥君だってあの短期間で頑張ったんだ
And Shiratori, you've tried so hard in such a short time.
ここまで来たら連載したいだろ
You want to get serialized after coming this far, right?
I-I do, but...
したいのは したいですけど
先生に無理させたり 迷惑がかかるなら
If it's too much of an inconvenience for Takagi...
それに 僕 親に反対されていて
Also, my parents are against it...
絵を描きたいなら留学しろって
They said that if I want to draw, I should study abroad.
それで白鳥君は マンガ描きたいのか留学したいのか どっちなんだ
So, do you want to draw manga or study abroad?
マンガは 描きたいですけど
I want to draw manga.
じゃあ 描けよ
Then draw!
高木に 「原作書いてくれ」って言えばいいじゃないか
Tell Takagi you want him to do the story!
何を迷う事があるんだ
Why are you hesitating?
白鳥君は分かってないかもしれないけど
Shiratori, you may not know, but Takagi does.
高木は 分かってるはず
連載を取るのがどれだけ大変な事か
He knows just how hard it is to get serialized.
どれだけの人が憧れ 挑戦して 敗れ 諦めていってるか
And how many people want it, fight for it,
but just break down and give up in the end.
こんなチャンス 自分から断るなんておかしいだろ
You can't refuse an opportunity like this!
僕も真城君と同じ意見だ
I feel the same as Mashiro.
Of course, both you and Takagi have talent.
もちろん 高木君 白鳥君 2人とも才能がある
しかし 連載というものはそれだけで取れるわけではない
But you can't become serialized on talent alone.
そうですね 「ジャック」で連載 簡単にできる事じゃない
That's right. Getting a Jack serialization isn't easy.
分かりました やってみます
Okay, then. I'll do it.
ただ 「PCP」に影響すると思ったら手を引く
But if it affects PCP, I'll pull out.
そこだけは 勘弁してほしい
I need you to understand that.
O-Of course!
もちろんです
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
本当に 「恋太」の原作やってみるでよかったんだよな
Is it really okay for me to write for Rabuta?
しつこいな やれって
Stop asking. Just do it.
俺も挑戦するから
I'm also going to challenge myself.
もう少し速く描けるようになったら
When I'm able to draw a bit faster...
1人で もう1作 描く
I'm going to draw another manga by myself!
Since you can't get an anime with me as your partner,
俺と組んでも アニメは無理だから 一人で やろうとしてんのか
you're going to do it yourself?
違うって
That's not it.
だったら 何で
Then why?
俺も挑戦したいんだ
I want to challenge myself.
亜城木夢叶のレベルアップのために
To improve Ashirogi Mutou.
2作描けるようになるには 相当 時間がかかるだろうけど
It may take some time to be able to draw two manga at once,
努力すれば必ず出来るようになる
but if I put all my effort into it, I know I can do it.
これができなきゃ エイジを超えるなんておこがましい
If I can't, then it'd be pointless to even think about surpassing Eiji!
下描き1ページだけで 93分43秒
A rough sketch of one page alone
takes me 93 minutes and 43 seconds.
このペースで 19ページだと 30時間近くかかる
At this pace, 19 pages will take me about 30 hours.
Without sacrificing quality...
質を落とさず いや 質を上げながら より速く
No, I have to be faster and improve the quality!
それを意識しながら ひたすら描くしかない
I have to keep that in mind as I draw!
シュン パリへの留学決めて いいですね
Shun, I can finalize your plans for studying abroad in Paris, correct?
留学はしません
I won't study abroad.
じゃあ パパの会社に
Then, you'll work at Dad's company?
それも しない
I won't do that either.
How long will you continue to be so unreasonable?
いつまで だだをこねてるの
どちらかに早く決めなさい
Decide on one or the other, quickly.
僕は マンガ家になります
I'm going to be a manga artist.
ふざけないで マンガ家なんて みっともない
Don't be ridiculous!
That profession is shameful.
I'm going to draw manga!
僕は マンガを描く
許してもらえないなら 家を出ます
If you won't allow it, I'll run away from home!
An innocent kid like you wouldn't be
able to make it out there alone.
シュンみたいな世間知らずが家を出て
一人でやってけるはずないじゃない
ごちそうさま
Thanks for dinner.
これ シュンが描いたの
Did you draw this, Shun?
シュンは 本当に絵が上手ね
You're really good at drawing.
そうだ パパにも見せてあげましょう
Let's show this to your dad.
ピース
Peace?
ピースたったら
Oh, Peace.
サイコーが2本 作画できるようになるには もう少し時間がかかる
It'll take Saikou a while before he's ready to draw two manga at once.
だったらそれができるようになるまでに 俺が原作をもう1本
So, until he can, I'll take on writing one more manga...
いや 無理か
Or is it impossible?
まず2本できるかどうか
I don't even know if I can handle two yet...
真城
Mashiro, something's up with Shiratori.
白鳥君 なんかおかしい
Huh? Like what?
どこが
なんか髪の毛べったりしてるし
His hair's kinda oily.
いつも いい匂いしてるのに 今日しない
And he always smells good, but today he doesn't.
よく観察してんな
You keep a close eye on him, don't you?
風邪で お風呂入ってないとか
Maybe he's sick and didn't take a bath last night?
1日って感じじゃないんだって
This doesn't seem like a one-day thing!
The Next Day
絶対 おかしいって 昨日と同じ服
This is definitely weird!
He's wearing the same clothes as yesterday.
なんか汚れてるし
And they're dirty!
俺も おかしいと思う
I think it's weird, too!
うん 分かった
O-Okay.
Shiratori, sorry, but can you stay a bit after work?
白鳥君 悪いけど 仕事終わったらちょっと残ってくれるかな
え はい
Uh, okay.
家出
You ran away from home?!
そのピースって 今どうしてるの
Where is Peace right now?
外で待ってます
He's waiting outside.
お父さんの会社に入るか 留学
So you can either work at your dad's company, or study abroad.
はい
Yes.
Shiratori, you want to be a manga artist, right?
白鳥君はマンガ家になりたいんだよね
はい だから家を出たんです
Yes!
That's why I ran away from home.
正直言うと 最初は絵さえ描ければと思っていたんですけど
Honestly, I thought I'd be happy as long as I could draw.
ネームを描いて それが 「ジャック」に載ったらうれしくてたまらなくて
But when I drew a storyboard that made it into Jack, I was so happy.
何百万人もの人が見てくれたんだと思うと やりがいがあるって
When I think about the millions of people that will be reading my work, I feel like it's all worth it.
その気持ちは すごく分かるけど
I understand that feeling, but you have to contact your family.
家には ちゃんと連絡しないと
大丈夫です
It's okay. They know I'm working at
your studio, and they have the address.
亜城木先生の所で働いている事も 住所も教えてあります
だけど 野宿は まずいよ
But you shouldn't be sleeping outdoors.
Right. If they find out about it, they'll be even more worried.
そんな事してるって知られたら もっと心配かける
はい
Yeah.
今日は あたしの実家に来なさい
Stay at my parents' house tonight.
そんな 迷惑じゃ
I couldn't inconvenience them like—
いいから いいから
It's fine.
パパ 不動産屋だから部屋も探してくれるし
My dad's a realtor, so he'll find you a place.
ね
Okay?
あ ありがとうございます
Thank you!
パパ これ見た
Dad, have you seen this?
The issue with Shun's manga in it?
シュンのマンガが載った号か
最近読んでないから見落としたよ
I haven't been reading it lately, so I missed it.
最近って
Lately?
いや 外で たまにな
I read it when I'm out sometimes.
Rabuta
& Peace
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
A fantasy
about a dog
that holds a
mysterious
power
これ シュンとピースなんだろうな
This is Shun and Peace, right?
Yeah.
それにしても すごいな シュン
Shun sure is something.
すっかり落ち着いたみたいでよかった
Things seem to have settled down. I'm glad.
真城先生
Mashiro?
このページ 教室に何人か生徒がいた方が いいですよね
We should probably draw some students in the background on this page, don't you think?
あ はい お願いします
Oh, you're right. Go ahead.
細かく下描きして一度見せた方がいいですか
Can I do a detailed sketch and then show it to you?
下描きしたら 一度見せるのは 当たり前
You should always show him the sketch!
Oh, sorry.
ごめんなさい
細かくって
Detailed?
自分の原稿だったら アタリしか取らず ペン入れしちゃうんです
On my own manuscript, I would ink in a rough sketch directly.
白鳥君 自分のやり方で マコト描いてくれないかな この原稿に
Shiratori, could you draw Makoto
using your method? On this page?
出来ました
I'm done.
えっ 速っ
He's fast!
これだけ
This is all?
Shun, that's enough. We're going home.
シュン いいかげんになさい 帰りますよ
僕は帰らない
I'm not going.
ちゃんと部屋も見つけました
I found my own apartment.
あの どうして マンガを描く事に反対なんでしょうか
Excuse me, but why are you so against him drawing manga?
白鳥家の長男にはふさわしくありません
It is an inappropriate vocation for the son of the Shiratori family.
やっぱり世間体なんだ
It's all about appearances in the end.
絵を描きたいなら美大に行け
If you want to draw, go to an art school.
美大に落ちたら留学しろ
If you don't get into art school, study abroad.
全部 体裁を気にして母さんが 敷いたレール
All according to the plan you've laid out for me that will keep up appearances.
画家だけが絵を描く仕事じゃない
There's more to art than painting.
僕には マンガの方が合ってる それが分かったんだ
I'm suited for manga.
I know that now.
自分の作品が認められてうれしかった
Getting my work recognized made me happy.
マンガを描く事が楽しいんだ
Drawing manga is fun!
そんなの所詮お絵描き遊びじゃない
Nonsense. It's just people playing at being artists.
We're not playing at anything!
遊びなんかじゃない
人生懸けて やってるんだ
We're staking our life on it!
How rude. Please refrain from butting in on our family affairs.
何ですか 人の家の事に口を出さないでちょうだい
ふさわしくないとか 遊びだとか
Saying manga is "inappropriate" and that we're "playing around"...
言いたい事 言ってくれますね
You've really done it now.
やってやる 白鳥君と力を合わせて すげものを
We'll do it!
Shiratori and I will work together to make something great.
白鳥家が誇れる作品を作ってみせる
Something the Shiratori family can be proud of!
Shiratori can do it.
白鳥君なら できます
絵に関しては僕の方が学ばせてもらってるところも あるんです
When it comes to art, even I can learn from him!
誰に言っても恥ずかしくない
He can become a manga artist that you're not embarrassed to talk about to anyone!
お母さんも誇りにできるマンガ家になれます
立派なマンガ描きより 売れない画家の方がまだいいと言っているんです
I'm saying that becoming an unpopular painter would be better than him becoming a popular manga artist.
こりゃ いくら話しても説得なんて無理だわ
We could talk all day and never convince her.
マンガは あなたが思っているほどくだらないものでは ありません
Manga isn't as worthless as you think it is.
Manga is a form of fine art!
マンガも描きようによっては芸術です
絵画などとは また違った
It's different from paintings—it's a form of expression that moves you and speaks directly to young people's hearts!
今の若者の心に ダイレクトに響き
感動さえ与えられる表現法
少なくとも 僕は芸術の一つ
At least I consider it a form of fine art when I draw it!
そう思って描いてます
マンガが芸術 ありえません
Manga as fine art? Impossible.
芸術とは ほど遠い大衆娯楽でしょ
Far from it. It's just entertainment for the masses.
否定しないで下さい
Don't put it down so harshly!
芸術でなければ いけないんだ
It has to be art!
シュン いつまでも だだをこねないで 絵を続けるならパリへ留学
Shun, stop being unreasonable. If you want to draw, study abroad in Paris.
いいですね
Do you understand?
私は マンガ いいと思う
I think manga is fine.
What are you talking about, Hitomi?
人美まで 何を言ってるの
私も「ジャック」のマンガ ママに隠れて よく読んでた
I've been hiding it from you, but I read Jack often.
Hitomi...
姉さん
Have you read Shun's manga?
シュンの描いたマンガ 読んだ
マンガなんて
How could I?
面白かったよ
It was good.
パパも すごいって感心してた
Dad said it was great, too.
Yeah.
シュンも反対を押し切ってこんなに頑張ろうとしてる
Shun is doing is best to stand up against you.
こんな事 今までなかった
He's never done that before.
家を出てまで やりたかった
He wanted it badly enough to run away.
そうよね シュン
Right, Shun?
I want to do it!
やりたい どうしても
No matter what!
You're serious, right?
本気なのよね
Yes. That's why I ran away from home.
本気だから家を出た
どうしても やらせてくれないなら 親子の縁を切ってでも
If you won't let me, I'll have to cut ties with my family.
シュン
Shun!
そこまでしなくても ママは分かってくれる
You won't have to do that. Mom will understand.
でも もし マンガを描くなら縁を切るって ママが言っても
But if she does insist on cutting ties with you for drawing manga...
シュン諦めたら そこで試合終了だよ
and you give up, that's game over.
お姉様 いかす
You go, girl!
もう 勝手にしなさい
Do as you like! Dear, Hitomi, we're leaving.
あなた 人美 帰りますよ
皆さん シュンの事 よろしくお願いします
Everyone, take care of Shun.
シュン お盆や お正月だけじゃなく
Shun, don't just pop in for O-bon and New Year's.
帰ってこられる時は帰ってきなさいよ
Come home whenever you can.
は はい
Right.
人美さん すてきな人だ
Hitomi is a wonderful girl.
よかったな
Good for you!
本当に これでよかったのよね
It'll be all right now.
はい
Yeah.
頑張って マンガ描きます 諦めたらそこで試合終了ですから
I'll try my best to draw a great manga.
If I give up, it's game over.
かっ 俺も言われたい
Man! I want someone to say that to me!
Ugh.
うわ 顔と髪のバランスが取れてない
I'm not getting the balance between the hair and the face.
白鳥君は これだけでペン入れを
Shiratori can start inking just from this...
このやり方が できれば
If I can do it like that...
どこまで下描きを簡略化できるか
How much can I simplify my rough sketches?
あとは慣れ
The rest is just practice.
昨日連載会議が あったわけだが
There was a serialization meeting yesterday.
「ラッコ11号」は 永遠に休みだ
Otter no. 11 is on an eternal break.
休みですか
A break!
やった
Finally, after four years as a manga artist, I've got a break!
マンガ家生活4年目にして ついに
えっ 永遠 それって
Eternal?
Does that mean...
アニメも終わってコミックスの売り上げが ダウン
The anime's over, and the volumes aren't selling.
ここらが潮時 あと6週だ
This was the right time. You've got six weeks left.
そこでだ
Therefore!
来年4月から人気作家による読切が 7週連続掲載
Next year, starting in April, they'll be publishing
one-shots from popular authors over seven weeks
人気作家読切祭に 平丸君はほぼ エントリーが決まっている
in an event called the Super Leaders Fest.
You're practically guaranteed entry.
じょ 冗談じゃない
N-No way!
連載が終わったら2年は休む そう決めてたんだ
If my serialization's over, I'm taking a two-year vacation!
I've already made up my mind!
蒼樹先生が エントリーしていると聞いても
Even if I tell you that Aoki is entering?
蒼樹さんも「青葉の頃」もマンネリ化と低迷で 終了決定
Aoki is?
Time of Blue Leaves is in a rut, and doing pretty poorly. It's getting canned.
次回作を見越してのエントリーなわけだが
You can use the excuse of aiming for a new serialization together to...
はい
Hello?
ひ 平丸です
I-It's Hiramaru.
お互い 残念な事になってしまいましたね
We're both pretty unlucky, it seems.
は はい
R-Right. But don't let it get you down.
でも気を落とさずに
僕も リーダーズフェスタに エントリーしたので 一緒に頑張りましょう
I also entered the Leaders Fest, so let's both do our best.
平丸さん 自分の連載も終わったのに 優しいんですね
Hiramaru... you're too kind, even though your serialization just ended, too.
え は はい
Um, er, thanks!
吉田氏 蒼樹さんが今度2人っきりで お茶でもと
Mr. Yoshida! Aoki said she wanted to go out to tea with me!
What?!
って 当たり前だ
I mean, of course! I told you, right?
言ったとおりだろ
はい 「落ち込んでいる時の女性はもろい最高に口説かれやすい」
Yep! "Depressed girls are fragile!"
"It's easier to put the moves on them!"
吉田氏のアドバイスどおりでした
Your advice was spot-on!
よし 平丸 残り6話と 読切のネームだ
All right, Hiramaru!
All we need now are your final six chapters and a storyboard for your one-shot!
分っかりました 吉田師範代
Right, Instructor Yoshida!
読切なんて ちょろいです
One-shots are a piece of cake.
人気作家読切祭
Super Leaders Fest?
Yeah. Among the entries are Hiramaru and Aoki, whose series were recently canceled.
エントリーしてるのは連載終了が決まった平丸先生と蒼樹先生
あと ベテランの新井先生と新妻君だ
And the veterans Arai and Niizuma are also participating.
新妻さん他に2本も連載してるのに
Even though Niizuma's got two series going already.
まっ 新妻君なら できるだろう
Well, Niizuma can probably pull it off.
本人も やりたがってるそうだ
It seems like he wants to do it.
その読切 僕たちも エントリーさせて下さい
Let us enter it, too!
いや 高木君は 「PCP」がある上に
Well, on top of PCP, Takagi's got Rabuta & Peace going into the serialization committee.
「恋太＆ピース」も連載会議に出そうとしているんだ 無理があるだろ
Wouldn't that be too much?
高木の負担が大きすぎるなら 僕一人でも
If it's too much of a burden on him, I'll do it alone!
いえ やります
No, I'll do it!
やらなくてはいけないと思います
I think I have to!
いけない
Have to?
服部さん 僕が「恋太」を やってなければ
Hattori, if I wasn't working on Rabuta & Peace, you wouldn't have objected, right?
この読切に反対しなかったはずですよね
It would be unfair to Mashiro if we couldn't participate because of me.
僕のせいで できないなら 真城に迷惑かけてる事になる
僕は あくまで亜城木夢叶なんです
We're Ashirogi Mutou to the end!
そうか
I see.
そうだな
That's right.
分かった 人気作家読切祭に エントリーさせる
Okay then! We'll enter the Super Leaders Fest!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
mogakinagara saikou no yume wo
The times when I fight and struggle and dream
katachi ni suru kono shunkan ga suki sa
of all the things I want in life is the best
tatakau you na te wo tsunagu you na
That's when I feel the bond between us and our strength to fight
kankaku ga shigekiteni da ne
Our view of the world overlaps and stimulates us
kousa shite
dakara motto migakou jibun rashiku arou
Let us polish ourselves, be more like how we should be
tsuzuita michi ni aru hazu
The future can be found on the path we walk
mirai wa
shinzuru mono ga chigau nakamatachi
My comrades believe in different things than me
Rival...and Friend!
butsukariau Pride
Our pride clashes
yuzurenai kore kara mo kokoro no mama susumou yo
I can't give up on it, I have to do what my heart commands me to do
junbi wa dekita
I'm ready
ikki ni kakeagaru tame no
I've got the unbending pride
akiramenai Pride
to run to the top now
hisshi nanda yo suki dakara suki wo mune ni susumu n da
This is my only choice, this is what I love and this is what I'll do
donna ashita ga matteru ka shiranai
I don't know what tomorrow will be like
asu mo
But I know that tomorrow, again,
bokura wa
girigiri
ganbatteru darou
we will do our best to get by
Next Time
Preview
リーダーズフェスタ 面白いことなっていきましたね
The Leaders Fest is turning out to be interesting.
明日を担う作家が競い 高めよう
It's wonderful to see authors
competing and raising each other up.
すばらしい
早く 僕の役職も高めてください
I wish someone would give me a raise!
Next time: Punch and Independence.
Punch and
Independence
班長になるのが切実の夢だ
Becoming the leader is a crucial dream!